<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Ahmad Adillaumam</title>
    <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ahmad Adillaumam</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://wewnumam.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph</url>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 10:38:43 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wewnumam.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>12 Easy Ways to Make Videos Significantly Better</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/12-easy-ways-to-make-videos-significantly-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 10:38:43 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/12-easy-ways-to-make-videos-significantly-better/</guid>
      <description>Think about Every Piece of the Picture When watching a video, we can only watch the direction of the camera. If the camera looks at the same thing for too long or is not looking at something the viewer wants to see, the viewer will get bored.
Sporting events on TV are usually captured with a dozen to dozens of different cameras-every few seconds moving to a different image. And each image focuses on new information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Design Document Format for Academic Purposes</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/game-design-document-format-for-academic-purposes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 08:35:19 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/game-design-document-format-for-academic-purposes/</guid>
      <description>Opening Page The cover page contains information including:
Title. The title in the form of the words &amp;ldquo;Game Design Document&amp;rdquo; is needed to name the document so that at a glance people can imply what is meant in the document. Game Title. In the form of an attachment to the game name either in the form of a logo or any form that can be read. Genre and Game Mode. Contains information about the genre and game mode—such as online or offline mode, and single-player or multi-player mode—that will be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Variable Names</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/the-power-of-variable-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 09:22:51 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/the-power-of-variable-names/</guid>
      <description>Meaningful Variable Names Choosing good names takes time but saves more than it takes.
Intention-Revealing Names The name should answer all big questions. It should tell you why it exists, what it does, and how it is used. If the name requires a comment, the name does not reveal the intent.
let d; // elapsed time in days We should choose the name that specifies what is being measured and the unit of that measurement:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Basic Requirements of a Game</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/10-key-quality-of-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 23:59:06 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/10-key-quality-of-games/</guid>
      <description>Why is a game said to be a game?
The answer is because it fulfills the key qualities of a game.
There are at least 10 important quality keys in a game, according to Jesse Schell in his book The Art of Game Design.
Games are played voluntarily (volunteer) There is no compulsion in playing a game. This means that the player has the control to freely join the game and leave the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>📚 I love phylosophy.
🧑‍💻 I&amp;rsquo;m presistent in software development.
🏷 I create value from content and design.
💻 People come to me for tech support.
&amp;hellip;
Still figuring out the intersection.
Check out my Linktree to know me more!
No bullshit quote. Just be clear about what we want need. ✌️</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ahmad Adillaumam - Designer Resume</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/ahmad-adillaumam-designer-resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/ahmad-adillaumam-designer-resume/</guid>
      <description>🛠 Skills Board game and video game design. Graphic design: Logo. Print media: board game, poster, book cover, business card, packaging. Social media kit. Digital painting. Video production director. Video editor. 🕓 Experience Freelance Graphic Designer 🗓️ 2019 - PRESENT
Designed poster, book cover, packaging design, and social media kit. Participated in logo design contest at sribu.com. Tools used: Inkscape, GIMP. Results obtained: People liked the minimalist design that I made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ahmad Adillaumam - Software Developer Resume</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/ahmad-adillaumam-software-developer-resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/ahmad-adillaumam-software-developer-resume/</guid>
      <description>🛠 Skills Video game development: Video game design. Game programming (Unity &amp;amp; HTML5). Web development: Front-End (HTML, CSS, Javascript) Back-End (Codeigniter, Laravel, NodeJS, Django). Database (MySQL, PostgreSQL). CMS (Wordpress, Hugo). Software modeling: Database design. API design and documentation. UI design. Management: Source code management. Program documentation. Project management. 🕓 Experience LKS Web Technology Prov. Central Java 🗓️ MARCH 2021
Speed test, building web features: CSS (responsive layout) Javascript (rgb color slider) PHP (captcha) Customizing Wordpress themes using CSS.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
