<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Career on Ahmad Adillaumam</title>
    <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/tags/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Career on Ahmad Adillaumam</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://wewnumam.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph</url>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 06:10:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wewnumam.github.io/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Having the Right Mindset as a Programmer</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/having-the-right-mindset-as-a-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 06:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/having-the-right-mindset-as-a-programmer/</guid>
      <description>Hi guys, especially my game developer friends on campus! Have you thought about what you will do after graduation? Do you have a plan? Are you interested in becoming a programmer? What have you done to develop your skills as a programmer, such as creating projects or diligently coding?
However, the question is, is that enough? With your current skills, who would want to hire you? There are hundreds or thousands of people with similar skills, so what makes you irreplaceable?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Having the Right Mindset to Survive in the Game Industry</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/having-the-right-mindset-to-survive-in-the-game-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 06:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/having-the-right-mindset-to-survive-in-the-game-industry/</guid>
      <description>The game industry is a challenging and complex field, and having the right mindset is crucial for survival and success. It&amp;rsquo;s important to have clear goals and start by giving our maximum effort, even if it seems small.
Here are some key mindsets to cultivate in order to thrive in the game industry:
Technical skills are not enough While technical skills are important, they alone are not sufficient to make a living or build a career in the game industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Money From Games</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/making-money-from-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 01:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/making-money-from-games/</guid>
      <description>There are many ways to make money from games, whether as a developer selling homemade games, a streamer entertaining an audience, or a player trading in-game items. In this article, we will explore five different ways to monetize the passion for gaming and turn it into a profitable venture. From developing and selling homemade games to offering gaming-related services, there are many opportunities to make money in the gaming industry.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
