<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>College on Ahmad Adillaumam</title>
    <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/tags/college/</link>
    <description>Recent content in College on Ahmad Adillaumam</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://wewnumam.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph</url>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 22:40:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wewnumam.github.io/tags/college/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Do People Play Games</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/why-do-people-play-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 22:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/why-do-people-play-games/</guid>
      <description>According to a study, people play games for a variety of reasons, including the opportunity to structure and change their internal experiences. Many adults enjoy the chance to fill their heads with thoughts and emotions unrelated to work or school, while others are drawn to the challenge and opportunity to test their abilities. Games offer a sense of efficiency and order that may be lacking in everyday life, and can provide a sense of excitement and relaxation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Design Document Format for Academic Purposes</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/game-design-document-format-for-academic-purposes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 08:35:19 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/game-design-document-format-for-academic-purposes/</guid>
      <description>Opening Page The cover page contains information including:
Title. The title in the form of the words &amp;ldquo;Game Design Document&amp;rdquo; is needed to name the document so that at a glance people can imply what is meant in the document. Game Title. In the form of an attachment to the game name either in the form of a logo or any form that can be read. Genre and Game Mode. Contains information about the genre and game mode—such as online or offline mode, and single-player or multi-player mode—that will be used.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
