<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Industry on Ahmad Adillaumam</title>
    <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/tags/industry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Industry on Ahmad Adillaumam</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://wewnumam.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph</url>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 03:11:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wewnumam.github.io/tags/industry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gametech STMM MMTC Graduate Profile</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/gametech-stmm-mmtc-graduate-profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 03:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/gametech-stmm-mmtc-graduate-profile/</guid>
      <description>Data Source:
https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vTYmi8HLvPPIhFxOu00NLTWU-R37X7oWtyQbvIeEkO9sJ_P8_C6mFJ6cRJbr_-k1WgoXFtxcmPa0bF5/pubhtml</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indonesian Game Developer Forums</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/indonesian-game-developer-forums/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 01:27:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/indonesian-game-developer-forums/</guid>
      <description>Assosiation Asosiasi Game Indonesia (AGI) Asosiasi Game Indonesia (AGI) is an organisation whose aim is to accelerate the growth of the Indonesian video game industry. Indie Games Group Indonesia (IGGI) A virtual community for Game Developers in Indonesia that aims to connect GameDevs at all levels. IGDA Indonesia The International Game Developers Association (IGDA) is the world’s largest nonprofit membership organization serving all individuals who create games. General Community Game Developer ID GameDeveloper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Having the Right Mindset to Survive in the Game Industry</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/having-the-right-mindset-to-survive-in-the-game-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 06:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/having-the-right-mindset-to-survive-in-the-game-industry/</guid>
      <description>The game industry is a challenging and complex field, and having the right mindset is crucial for survival and success. It&amp;rsquo;s important to have clear goals and start by giving our maximum effort, even if it seems small.
Here are some key mindsets to cultivate in order to thrive in the game industry:
Technical skills are not enough While technical skills are important, they alone are not sufficient to make a living or build a career in the game industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gameseed Roadshow Key Points</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/gameseed-roadshow-key-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 03:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/gameseed-roadshow-key-points/</guid>
      <description>Adam Ardisasmita The gaming industry&amp;rsquo;s revenue and export numbers are much larger than other entertainment/content industries (music, movies, etc.). Mobile games account for 45% in 2021 and 53% in 2022 of the global gaming market. Indonesians spend 25 trillion rupiah a year on games, mostly to get items that increase social strata in games. Challenges of the gaming industry in Indonesia: the comparison between the spending of Indonesian gamers on games and the income of Indonesian game developers is still very far (1000:1).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
