<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Game Design on Ahmad Adillaumam</title>
    <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/tags/game-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Game Design on Ahmad Adillaumam</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://wewnumam.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph</url>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 22:40:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wewnumam.github.io/tags/game-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Do People Play Games</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/why-do-people-play-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 22:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/why-do-people-play-games/</guid>
      <description>According to a study, people play games for a variety of reasons, including the opportunity to structure and change their internal experiences. Many adults enjoy the chance to fill their heads with thoughts and emotions unrelated to work or school, while others are drawn to the challenge and opportunity to test their abilities. Games offer a sense of efficiency and order that may be lacking in everyday life, and can provide a sense of excitement and relaxation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Game Designer Mistakes</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/top-10-game-designer-mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 19:11:18 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/top-10-game-designer-mistakes/</guid>
      <description>As a game designer, it&amp;rsquo;s important to be aware of common pitfalls and mistakes that can hinder the success of your projects. By avoiding these mistakes, you can increase your chances of creating successful and enjoyable games that players will love. Here are the top 10 mistakes game designers should avoid:
Huge Project without Portfolio Starting with a large, ambitious project without a portfolio of smaller, completed games can be risky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Purpose of Games</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/the-purpose-of-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 05:49:40 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/the-purpose-of-games/</guid>
      <description>Games serve many different purposes and can be enjoyed for a variety of reasons. Some people play games as a form of entertainment, to pass the time, or to socialize with friends and family. Others play games to challenge themselves or to improve their skills in a particular area. Still others play games as a way to relax and destress after a long day.
Purposes for games in different contexts:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Basic Requirements of a Game</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/10-key-quality-of-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 23:59:06 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/10-key-quality-of-games/</guid>
      <description>Why is a game said to be a game?
The answer is because it fulfills the key qualities of a game.
There are at least 10 important quality keys in a game, according to Jesse Schell in his book The Art of Game Design.
Games are played voluntarily (volunteer) There is no compulsion in playing a game. This means that the player has the control to freely join the game and leave the game.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
