<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Game Design on Ahmad Adillaumam</title>
    <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/tags/game-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Game Design on Ahmad Adillaumam</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ahmad Adillaumam</title>
      <url>https://wewnumam.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph</url>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.1</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 23:07:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://wewnumam.github.io/tags/game-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Publisher Expectations for Your Game Pitch</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/understanding-publisher-expectations-for-your-game-pitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 23:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/understanding-publisher-expectations-for-your-game-pitch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When presenting your game to publishers, the primary objective of your pitch is to effectively communicate your game and convince stakeholders of its grand vision. Understanding the types of game pitch decks and the key components that publishers expect can significantly enhance your chances of securing their interest and support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;types-of-game-pitch-decks&#34;&gt;Types of Game Pitch Decks:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presenting pitch deck:&lt;/strong&gt; This type of pitch is used for direct presentations to individuals or groups and should be concise and straightforward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sent-out pitch deck&lt;/strong&gt;: This pitch is indirectly sent via email and should provide more extensive information to compensate for the absence of direct interaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-components-of-a-game-pitch&#34;&gt;Key Components of a Game Pitch:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; This section should contain the game&amp;rsquo;s concept, game design elements, and sample artwork. It serves as a snapshot of what your game is all about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost, Opportunities, and Production Roadmap:&lt;/strong&gt; This component outlines the potential profitability, marketing strategies, key milestones, and budget allocation for the game&amp;rsquo;s production.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Profile:&lt;/strong&gt; Highlight the achievements or relevant portfolio of your team members to showcase their expertise and experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pro-tips&#34;&gt;Pro Tips:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unique Game Concept and Market Potential:&lt;/strong&gt; Publishers are more likely to engage with games that offer unique experiences, although they also bear higher risks. Publishers will be interested in your game if it has a market demand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understand Player Motivation:&lt;/strong&gt; Clearly explain the objectives and factors that will captivate players. What makes your game compelling and attractive?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Showcase Engaging Game Art:&lt;/strong&gt; Include the best key points of your game art to convey the vibe and visual appeal of your game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know Your Market Position:&lt;/strong&gt; Understand the competitive landscape and highlight how your game stands out within the market of similar games. Ensure it is advantageous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Committed Development Team:&lt;/strong&gt; Demonstrate that you have a dedicated full-time development team committed to your game project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;basic-rule-of-thumb&#34;&gt;Basic Rule of Thumb:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grab Attention Early:&lt;/strong&gt; Ensure the most captivating aspects of your game are presented within the first 1-2 minutes of your pitch to capture the publisher&amp;rsquo;s interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emphasize Fun and Appeal:&lt;/strong&gt; Clearly explain why your game is fun and what makes it appealing to players.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appropriate Scope and Pricing:&lt;/strong&gt; Convince publishers that your game has a suitable scope and reasonable pricing by explaining the costs and opportunities involved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlight Team Achievements:&lt;/strong&gt; Introduce the track record and accomplishments of your team members to establish their capability to deliver the game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crafting an effective game pitch requires careful attention to the expectations of publishers. By incorporating the suggested components and adhering to the provided tips, you can enhance your chances of successfully pitching your game and securing the support of a publisher. Remember, a compelling pitch can significantly impact the trajectory of your game&amp;rsquo;s development and success in the competitive gaming industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Run Your First Playtest</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/how-to-run-your-first-playtest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 21:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/how-to-run-your-first-playtest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To run your first playtest, it&amp;rsquo;s important to have a clear understanding of your target audience and the type of game you&amp;rsquo;re creating. This will help you to choose the right group of playtesters and create a test scenario that closely simulates the final product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the playtest, prepare a list of questions that you want to ask your playtesters, and set up a system for collecting feedback. This can be done through a survey or through verbal feedback during the playtest. Additionally, make sure you have all the necessary materials and equipment ready, such as game boards, cards, dice, and any other components that are needed for the game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Do People Play Games</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/why-do-people-play-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 22:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/why-do-people-play-games/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to a study, people play games for a variety of reasons, including the opportunity to structure and change their internal experiences. Many adults enjoy the chance to fill their heads with thoughts and emotions unrelated to work or school, while others are drawn to the challenge and opportunity to test their abilities. Games offer a sense of efficiency and order that may be lacking in everyday life, and can provide a sense of excitement and relaxation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Game Designer Mistakes</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/top-10-game-designer-mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 19:11:18 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/top-10-game-designer-mistakes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a game designer, it&amp;rsquo;s important to be aware of common pitfalls and mistakes that can hinder the success of your projects. By avoiding these mistakes, you can increase your chances of creating successful and enjoyable games that players will love. Here are the top 10 mistakes game designers should avoid:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;huge-project-without-portfolio&#34;&gt;Huge Project without Portfolio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with a large, ambitious project without a portfolio of smaller, completed games can be risky. It&amp;rsquo;s important to build a portfolio of completed projects to showcase your skills and capabilities before tackling a larger project. A portfolio can also help you demonstrate your ability to complete projects and can be used to attract funding or partners for larger projects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Purpose of Games</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/the-purpose-of-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 05:49:40 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/the-purpose-of-games/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Games serve many different purposes and can be enjoyed for a variety of reasons. Some people play games as a form of entertainment, to pass the time, or to socialize with friends and family. Others play games to challenge themselves or to improve their skills in a particular area. Still others play games as a way to relax and destress after a long day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purposes for games in different contexts:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Basic Requirements of a Game</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/10-key-quality-of-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 23:59:06 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/10-key-quality-of-games/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why is a game said to be a game?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is because it fulfills the key qualities of a game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are at least 10 important quality keys in a game, according to Jesse Schell in his book &lt;em&gt;The Art of Game Design&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;games-are-played-voluntarily-volunteer&#34;&gt;Games are played voluntarily (&lt;em&gt;volunteer&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no compulsion in playing a game. This means that the player has the control to freely join the game and leave the game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
