<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Business on Ahmad Adillaumam</title>
    <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/tags/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business on Ahmad Adillaumam</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ahmad Adillaumam</title>
      <url>https://wewnumam.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph</url>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.1</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 03:23:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://wewnumam.github.io/tags/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gameseed Roadshow Key Points</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/gameseed-roadshow-key-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 03:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/gameseed-roadshow-key-points/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;adam-ardisasmita&#34;&gt;Adam Ardisasmita&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xoeit2NdiHA?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The gaming industry&amp;rsquo;s revenue and export numbers are much larger than other entertainment/content industries (music, movies, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile games account for 45% in 2021 and 53% in 2022 of the global gaming market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indonesians spend 25 trillion rupiah a year on games, mostly to get items that increase social strata in games.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Challenges of the gaming industry in Indonesia: the comparison between the spending of Indonesian gamers on games and the income of Indonesian game developers is still very far (1000:1).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obstacles in making games: lack of funds (66.7%), lack of human resources (44.4%), lack of skills (36.1%), others (26.4%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why there are few successful local game developers in Indonesia: Business Model; Market Visibility; Access To Funding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business model challenges: premium (sales conversion &amp;amp; product experience) and freemium (live ops &amp;amp; reading data)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Market visibility challenge: pc gamers are more open to games with similar genres while mobile gamers tend to be enthusiastic about 1 game only. Longer life time and limited storage space make mobile gamers rarely look for other games in the same genre.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access to funding challenges: premium (market similar to publisher) and freemium (market validation before funding).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trends in mobile games: Game as a Service (live service and in-app purchase) revenue is greater than full game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trends in game purchasing power in developing countries: very sensitive to price, micro-transactions are more suitable than one-time purchases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay attention to the development of cloud gaming and subscription based model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other strategies that can be taken: capitalize on viral trends, local wisdom, niche markets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In terms of revenue, it makes more sense to target the global market, but in the local market, we know the market better, so competition is easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relatibility is a challenge when promoting local wisdom, the unique selling point must be generally accepted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Game trends are changing, all market segments need games, make sure to test games to the right target market.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Money From Games</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/making-money-from-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 01:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/making-money-from-games/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to make money from games, whether as a developer selling homemade games, a streamer entertaining an audience, or a player trading in-game items. In this article, we will explore five different ways to monetize the passion for gaming and turn it into a profitable venture. From developing and selling homemade games to offering gaming-related services, there are many opportunities to make money in the gaming industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
