<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Ahmad Adillaumam</title>
    <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Ahmad Adillaumam</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://wewnumam.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph</url>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 06:10:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Having the Right Mindset as a Programmer</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/having-the-right-mindset-as-a-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 06:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/having-the-right-mindset-as-a-programmer/</guid>
      <description>Hi guys, especially my game developer friends on campus! Have you thought about what you will do after graduation? Do you have a plan? Are you interested in becoming a programmer? What have you done to develop your skills as a programmer, such as creating projects or diligently coding?
However, the question is, is that enough? With your current skills, who would want to hire you? There are hundreds or thousands of people with similar skills, so what makes you irreplaceable?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indonesian Game Developer Forums</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/indonesian-game-developer-forums/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 01:27:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/indonesian-game-developer-forums/</guid>
      <description>Assosiation Asosiasi Game Indonesia (AGI) Asosiasi Game Indonesia (AGI) is an organisation whose aim is to accelerate the growth of the Indonesian video game industry. Indie Games Group Indonesia (IGGI) A virtual community for Game Developers in Indonesia that aims to connect GameDevs at all levels. IGDA Indonesia The International Game Developers Association (IGDA) is the world’s largest nonprofit membership organization serving all individuals who create games. General Community Game Developer ID GameDeveloper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Publisher Expectations for Your Game Pitch</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/understanding-publisher-expectations-for-your-game-pitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 23:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/understanding-publisher-expectations-for-your-game-pitch/</guid>
      <description>When presenting your game to publishers, the primary objective of your pitch is to effectively communicate your game and convince stakeholders of its grand vision. Understanding the types of game pitch decks and the key components that publishers expect can significantly enhance your chances of securing their interest and support.
Types of Game Pitch Decks: Presenting pitch deck: This type of pitch is used for direct presentations to individuals or groups and should be concise and straightforward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Having the Right Mindset to Survive in the Game Industry</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/having-the-right-mindset-to-survive-in-the-game-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 06:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/having-the-right-mindset-to-survive-in-the-game-industry/</guid>
      <description>The game industry is a challenging and complex field, and having the right mindset is crucial for survival and success. It&amp;rsquo;s important to have clear goals and start by giving our maximum effort, even if it seems small.
Here are some key mindsets to cultivate in order to thrive in the game industry:
Technical skills are not enough While technical skills are important, they alone are not sufficient to make a living or build a career in the game industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gameseed Roadshow Key Points</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/gameseed-roadshow-key-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 03:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/gameseed-roadshow-key-points/</guid>
      <description>Adam Ardisasmita The gaming industry&amp;rsquo;s revenue and export numbers are much larger than other entertainment/content industries (music, movies, etc.). Mobile games account for 45% in 2021 and 53% in 2022 of the global gaming market. Indonesians spend 25 trillion rupiah a year on games, mostly to get items that increase social strata in games. Challenges of the gaming industry in Indonesia: the comparison between the spending of Indonesian gamers on games and the income of Indonesian game developers is still very far (1000:1).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Run Your First Playtest</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/how-to-run-your-first-playtest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 21:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/how-to-run-your-first-playtest/</guid>
      <description>To run your first playtest, it&amp;rsquo;s important to have a clear understanding of your target audience and the type of game you&amp;rsquo;re creating. This will help you to choose the right group of playtesters and create a test scenario that closely simulates the final product.
Before the playtest, prepare a list of questions that you want to ask your playtesters, and set up a system for collecting feedback. This can be done through a survey or through verbal feedback during the playtest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Do People Play Games</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/why-do-people-play-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 22:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/why-do-people-play-games/</guid>
      <description>According to a study, people play games for a variety of reasons, including the opportunity to structure and change their internal experiences. Many adults enjoy the chance to fill their heads with thoughts and emotions unrelated to work or school, while others are drawn to the challenge and opportunity to test their abilities. Games offer a sense of efficiency and order that may be lacking in everyday life, and can provide a sense of excitement and relaxation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Money From Games</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/making-money-from-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 01:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/making-money-from-games/</guid>
      <description>There are many ways to make money from games, whether as a developer selling homemade games, a streamer entertaining an audience, or a player trading in-game items. In this article, we will explore five different ways to monetize the passion for gaming and turn it into a profitable venture. From developing and selling homemade games to offering gaming-related services, there are many opportunities to make money in the gaming industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Tips for Writing Clear and Concise Git Commit Messages</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/5-tips-for-writing-clear-and-concise-git-commit-messages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 05:27:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/5-tips-for-writing-clear-and-concise-git-commit-messages/</guid>
      <description>Writing good commit messages is an important practice that can help other people understand the changes that you have made and why. Here are some tips for writing better commit messages:
Use a clear and descriptive subject line The first line of the commit message should be a short and concise summary of the changes that you have made. Keep it to around 50 characters or less. This will help other developers quickly understand the changes that you have made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Tips for Creating Clean Code</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/5-tips-for-creating-clean-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 05:39:10 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/5-tips-for-creating-clean-code/</guid>
      <description>Clean code is code that is easy to read, understand, and maintain. It follows a set of coding standards and principles that aim to make the code as readable and maintainable as possible.
Clean code is important because it helps reduce the time and effort required to understand and modify the codebase, and it makes it easier to add new features or fix bugs. It also promotes collaboration and reduces the risk of introducing new issues when modifying the code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Game Designer Mistakes</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/top-10-game-designer-mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 19:11:18 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/top-10-game-designer-mistakes/</guid>
      <description>As a game designer, it&amp;rsquo;s important to be aware of common pitfalls and mistakes that can hinder the success of your projects. By avoiding these mistakes, you can increase your chances of creating successful and enjoyable games that players will love. Here are the top 10 mistakes game designers should avoid:
Huge Project without Portfolio Starting with a large, ambitious project without a portfolio of smaller, completed games can be risky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Purpose of Games</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/the-purpose-of-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 05:49:40 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/the-purpose-of-games/</guid>
      <description>Games serve many different purposes and can be enjoyed for a variety of reasons. Some people play games as a form of entertainment, to pass the time, or to socialize with friends and family. Others play games to challenge themselves or to improve their skills in a particular area. Still others play games as a way to relax and destress after a long day.
Purposes for games in different contexts:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syntatic Sugars | C# Hidden Features</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/syntatic-sugars-csharp-hidden-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 18:24:03 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/syntatic-sugars-csharp-hidden-features/</guid>
      <description>Note:
To be able to use these features we need at least C# version 7 and above or Unity 2018 and above.
Ternary Operator In computer programming, the ternary conditional operator is a ternary operator that is part of the syntax for basic conditional expressions in several programming languages.It is commonly referred to as the conditional operator, ternary if, or inline if.
An expression a ? b : c evaluates to b if the value of a is true, and otherwise to c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Easy Ways to Make Videos Significantly Better</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/12-easy-ways-to-make-videos-significantly-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 10:38:43 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/12-easy-ways-to-make-videos-significantly-better/</guid>
      <description>Think about Every Piece of the Picture When watching a video, we can only watch the direction of the camera. If the camera looks at the same thing for too long or is not looking at something the viewer wants to see, the viewer will get bored.
Sporting events on TV are usually captured with a dozen to dozens of different cameras-every few seconds moving to a different image. And each image focuses on new information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Design Document Format for Academic Purposes</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/game-design-document-format-for-academic-purposes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 08:35:19 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/game-design-document-format-for-academic-purposes/</guid>
      <description>Opening Page The cover page contains information including:
Title. The title in the form of the words &amp;ldquo;Game Design Document&amp;rdquo; is needed to name the document so that at a glance people can imply what is meant in the document. Game Title. In the form of an attachment to the game name either in the form of a logo or any form that can be read. Genre and Game Mode. Contains information about the genre and game mode—such as online or offline mode, and single-player or multi-player mode—that will be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Variable Names</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/the-power-of-variable-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 09:22:51 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/the-power-of-variable-names/</guid>
      <description>Meaningful Variable Names Choosing good names takes time but saves more than it takes.
Intention-Revealing Names The name should answer all big questions. It should tell you why it exists, what it does, and how it is used. If the name requires a comment, the name does not reveal the intent.
let d; // elapsed time in days We should choose the name that specifies what is being measured and the unit of that measurement:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Basic Requirements of a Game</title>
      <link>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/10-key-quality-of-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 23:59:06 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wewnumam.github.io/articles/10-key-quality-of-games/</guid>
      <description>Why is a game said to be a game?
The answer is because it fulfills the key qualities of a game.
There are at least 10 important quality keys in a game, according to Jesse Schell in his book The Art of Game Design.
Games are played voluntarily (volunteer) There is no compulsion in playing a game. This means that the player has the control to freely join the game and leave the game.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
